A Finding Aid to the Una Hanbury Papers, 1910-1994, bulk 1966-1990, in the Archives of American Art AAA.hanbuna
Archives of American Art
Una Hanbury papers
1910-1994
AAA.hanbuna
Archives of American Art
5.3 Linear feet
The papers of Una Hanbury measure 5.3 linear feet and date from 1910 to 1994, with the bulk of the material from 1966 to 1990. The collection documents the sculptor's career and the dispersal of her estate through business records, project files, subject files, printed material, and photographs. There is also a small amount of material relating to her personal life including correspondence with friends and family and photographs from various stages of her life.
Una Hanbury
Biographical/Historical note
Una Hanbury (1904-1990) was a sculptor in Washington, D.C. and Santa Fe, New Mexico. Hanbury was born in Middlesex, England, in 1904; the incorrect birth date of 1909 that she submitted to Who's Who and other biographical reference sources is cited in numerous published articles. Hanbury [née Rawnsley] exhibited artistic talent as a young child and received instruction from animal artist Frank Calderon. After graduation from London's Polytechnic School of Art, she studied for three years at the Royal Academy. Jacob Epstein was her most influential teacher.
Soon after completing her formal education, Una Rawnsley became Una Hanbury and devoted herself full-time to being a wife and mother. During World War II she left England for Bermuda and brought her family to the United States once the war was over. Hanbury settled in Washington, D.C., where she resumed her sculpting career, completing many large scale commissions for public buildings such as the Medical Examiners Building, Baltimore, and St. Mark's Lutheran Church, Springfield, Virginia, among others. She developed a fine reputation as a portrait sculptor, and commissions included busts of Rachel Carson, Enrico Fermi, Buckminster Fuller, Laura Gilpin, Richard Neutra, Georgia O'Keeffe, Robert Oppenheimer, S. Dillon Ripley, and Andrés Segovia. In addition, animals--particularly horses--were a favorite subject since childhood; sculptures were commissioned by several zoos, and horse portraits often were commissioned by owners.
In 1970, Una Hanbury relocated to Santa Fe, New Mexico, where she continued working well into old age and became a significant force in the art life of that region.
Scope and Contents note
The papers of Una Hanbury measure 5.3 linear feet and date from 1910 to 1994, with the bulk of the material from 1966 to 1990. The collection documents the sculptor's career and the dispersal of her estate through business records, project files, subject files, printed material, and photographs. There is also a small amount of material relating to her personal life including correspondence with friends and family and photographs from various stages of her life.
Arrangement note
The collection is arranged into seven series.
Series 1: Personal Papers, 1926-1983 (Box 1; 4 folders)
Series 2: Business Records, 1965-1991 (Boxes 1-2; 1.2 linear feet)
Series 3: Project Files, 1961-1992 (Boxes 2-3; 1.8 linear feet)
Series 4: Subject Files, circa 1924-1985 (Box 4, OV 7; 1.0 linear feet)
Series 5: Estate of Una Hanbury, 1990-1994 (Boxes 4-5; 0.6 linear feet)
Series 6: Printed Material, 1926-1990 (Box 5; 0.4 linear feet)
Series 7: Photographs, 1910-1991 (Boxes 5-6, 0.3 linear feet)
Immediate Source of Acquisition note
The Una Hanbury papers were donated to the Archives of American Art by the artist's daughter, Jillian Poole, in 1999 and 2006.
Conditions Governing Access note
Use of original papers requires an appointment and is limited to the Archives' Washington, D.C., Research Center. Use of archival audiovisual recordings with no duplicate access copy requires advance notice. Contact Reference Services for more information.
Carson, Rachel, 1907-1964; Fuller, R. Buckminster (Richard Buckminster), 1895-; Gilpin, Laura; O'Keeffe, Georgia, 1887-1986; Oppenheimer, J. Robert, 1904-1967; Ripley, Sidney Dillon, 1913-2001; Royal Academy of Arts (Great Britain); Saunders Sculpture International; Segovia, Andrés, 1893-; Animal sculptors--New Mexico; Animal sculptors--Washington (D.C.); Animal sculpture; Photographs; Portrait sculpture, American; Portrait sculpture--20th century--United States; Sculptors; Women sculptors--New Mexico; Women sculptors--Washington (D.C.)
- Personal Papers, 1926-1983; Series 1; 4 Folders Box 1
  Scope and Contents note
  The Personal Papers series begins with Hanbury's correspondence with family and friends. Memorabilia, comprised mainly of printed material, includes a brochure about Chelsea Pottery in Nassau run by her relative David Rawnsley, an announcement of daughter Jillian's marriage, a program of Queen Elizabeth's coronation, and theater programs. Public speaking records include by-laws and membership lists of the Capital Speakers Club, programs of the Capital Public Speaking Classes, speech notes, and instructor's comments. The series also contains some pencil drawings by Una Hanbury, executed 1926 to 1928, and a silkscreen by her grandson, Colin Poole, from 1970.
  Arrangement note
  The series is arranged alphabetically by folder title, and material within each folder is arranged chronologically.
  - Correspondence, 1957-1983, undated (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Memorabilia, 1953-1971 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Public Speaking Class, 1953-1955 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Works of Art, 1926-1970, undated (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Business Records, 1965-1991, undated; Series 2; 1.2 Linear feet Boxes 1-2
  Business records documenting the career of Una Hanbury consist of correspondence with clients, dealers, and foundries, and include various gallery and associate files, consignment records, casting records, certificates of authenticity, speeches, writings, and a video-recorded sculpture demonstration on VHS from 1990.
  - Adobe Walls, 1984 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Albuquerque Museum of Art, History and Science, 1981-1989 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Amundson, Rand, 1970-1979, undated (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Appraisals, 1982-1987, undated (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Art In Public Places, 1985-1988 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Atwell Fine Art, 1988-1989 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Baker Gallery, 1972-1982, undated (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Biographical, 1980-1991, undated (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Brandywine Gallery, 1984-1986, undated (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Carson Gallery of Western American Art, 1978-1983, undated (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Casting Records, 1979-1990 (Box 1, Folder 15-17)
    A-Z, by title; see also names of individual foundries.
  - Certificates of Authenticity, 1976-1990 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Certificates of Authenticity, Paperweights, 1982 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Correspondence, Business, 1979-1990, undated (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Correspondence, General, 1971-1988, undated (Box 1, Folder 21)
    Correspondence regarding publications and speeches; letters to editors and politicians.
  - Decker, undated (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - DuPont, Elizabeth N., 1988-1989 (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Egan, Betty, 1987-1988 (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Exhibitions, 1966-1988, undated (Box 1, Folder 25)
    See also names of individual galleries and museums.
  - French & Co., 1982-1983 (Box 1, Folder 26)
    Nick French
  - Galleries, Miscellaneous, 1985, undated (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - Gallery A, 1980-1982 (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - Gordon Gallery, 1988-1989 (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - Hackett, Dwight, 1979-1989, undated (Box 1, Folder 30)
    Art Foundry
  - Huff's Gallery of Fine Art, 1980-1985, undated (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - Inventories, 1983-1985 (Box 1, Folder 32)
  - Krasnow, Frances, 1988-1989 (Box 1, Folder 33)
  - Lenkin, Melvin, 1987-1988 (Box 1, Folder 34)
  - Loveland High Plains Arts Council, 1992 (Box 1, Folder 35)
  - Merrill Gallery, 1985-1987, undated (Box 1, Folder 36)
  - Montgomery, George, 1988 (Box 1, Folder 37)
  - Morris Singer Foundry, Ltd., 1983 (Box 1, Folder 38)
  - Munson Gallery, 1982-1986, undated (Box 1, Folder 39)
  - Murphy, Sallye and Bill, 1986-1987 (Box 1, Folder 40)
  - National Sculpture Society, 1981, undated (Box 1, Folder 41)
  - Norma Wright Gallery, 1984-1987, undated (Box 1, Folder 42)
  - Notes, Miscellaneous, circa 1985-1989 (Box 1, Folder 43)
  - O'Keeffe, Georgia, 1967-1969 (Box 1, Folder 44)
  - J. W. Parks Gallery, 1979-1987 (Box 1, Folder 45)
  - Photographs on Loan, 1970-1987, undated (Box 1, Folder 46)
  - Portraits, Inc., 1983 (Box 1, Folder 47)
  - Possible Jobs, 1966-1988, undated (Box 1, Folder 48)
  - Price Lists, 1976-1989, undated (Box 1, Folder 49)
  - Private Stock Gallery, 1984, undated (Box 1, Folder 50)
  - Publicity, 1973-1989 (Box 1, Folder 51)
  - Rawson, Margaret, 1983-1985 (Box 1, Folder 52)
  - Robertson Gallery, 1988-1989 (Box 1, Folder 53)
  - Rosenquist Galleries, Inc., 1984-1986, undated (Box 1, Folder 54)
  - Rounds, Betty, 1982-1988 (Box 1, Folder 55)
  - Sales (Galleries), 1982-1984 (Box 1, Folder 56)
  - Sales (Personal), 1966-1990, undated (Box 1, Folder 57-58)
  - Sculpture Demontration, 1990; 1 Videocassettes (VHS) (Box 1, Folder 59)
  - Sculpture Registers, undated (Box 2, Folder 1-2)
    A-Z, by title, and "single items;" A-Z by gallery or other location.
  - Shidoni Foundry, Inc., 1977-1986 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Shinkle, Judith C., 1975 (Box 2, Folder 4)
    New Directions in Art, Inc.
  - Speeches by Hanbury-Notes, 1966-1967, undated (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Twyman, Margaret, 1982-1983 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Who's Who in America, Inc., 1980-1984, undated (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Wichita Gallery of Fine Art, 1980-1984 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Wilcrest Green Gallery, circa 1982 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Wright, Mary, 1986-1987 (Box 2, Folder 10)
    Medicine Wheel
  - Writings by Hanbury, circa 1970 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Zoos, 1965-1985, undated (Box 2, Folder 12)
- Project Files, 1961-1992, undated; Series 3; 1.8 Linear feet Boxes 2-3
  Unless otherwise noted, files include photographs--in fact, many consist of photographs only. If other record types such as correspondence, printed material, certificates of authenticity, casting records, sketches, 35-mm slides, color transparencies, and negatives are present, this information is noted for each title. Dates indicated reflect the contents of the folder, which may or may not correspond to the date of execution of the particular work.
  Project files are arranged alphabetically by title/commission. Material within each folder is arranged chronologically.
  - African Spring, undated (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Alcebiades, undated (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Baby Portraits, undated (Box 2, Folder 15)
    Portraits of Jillian and Sheila King.
  - The Babysitter, undated (Box 2, Folder 16)
    Includes correspondence and an exhibition brochure.
  - Baryshnikov and McBride, undated (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Berthe, Hans, 1975-1976, undated (Box 2, Folder 18)
    Includes correspondence and sketches.
  - Birds, undated (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - Boys Playing, 1983 (Box 2, Folder 20)
    Includes sales record.
  - Brammer, Mary, 1979 (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - Brandt Children, undated (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - Brave New World, 1974-1980 (Box 2, Folder 23)
    Includes correspondence and a brochure.
  - Bristlecone Pine Trees, circa 1977 (Box 2, Folder 24)
    Includes color transparencies, negative, and descriptive text.
  - Buffalo, 1974-1980 (Box 2, Folder 25)
    Includes casting record, news clippings, and a 35-mm slide.
  - Buffalo Calf-Lying, 1981-1983 (Box 2, Folder 26)
    Includes sales record and a 35-mm slide.
  - Buffalo Calf-Standing, 1977-1981 (Box 2, Folder 27)
  - Bull and Bear, 1965-1966 (Box 2, Folder 28)
    Includes news clipping.
  - Burro with Twins, undated (Box 2, Folder 29)
  - Burros, 1974-1975 (Box 2, Folder 30)
    Includes correspondence.
  - Calliope, 1975-1982 (Box 2, Folder 31)
    Includes casting records and news clipping.
  - Canyon de Chelly, circa 1980 (Box 2, Folder 32)
    No photographs. Includes a casting record.
  - Carmichael, Leonard, 1975-1977, undated (Box 2, Folder 33)
    Includes correspondence, check stubs, receipt, news clipping, and negatives.
  - Carson, Rachel, 1982-1987 (Box 2, Folder 34)
    Includes sales record, correspondence, and a brochure.
  - Cats, circa 1982 (Box 2, Folder 35)
    Found here are files for Sheba, Mehitabel, Kittens Playing, and Cats. Includes negatives and a 35-mm slide.
  - Children Playing, Relief, undated (Box 2, Folder 36)
  - Children's Portraits, undated (Box 2, Folder 37)
    Portraits of Josephine Coatsworth and three others. Includes a 35-mm slide.
  - Communication, undated (Box 2, Folder 38)
  - Communion Table, Wheaton Presbyterian Church (MD), undated (Box 2, Folder 39)
  - Compassion, 1969 (Box 2, Folder 40)
    Includes news clippings and correspondence.
  - Concha, 1975 (Box 2, Folder 41)
    Includes news clippings, biographical information, and publicity for unveiling.
  - Crofter's Daughter, undated (Box 2, Folder 42)
    Includes negatives.
  - Dancers, 1983 (Box 2, Folder 43)
    Includes invoice for photographs, negatives, and 35-mm slides.
  - Dancing on the Beach, undated (Box 2, Folder 44)
  - Desert Patterns, 1983 (Box 2, Folder 45)
    No photographs. Includes negatives and sales record.
  - Dog (Boxer), undated (Box 2, Folder 46)
  - Dryden, Hugh, undated (Box 2, Folder 47)
    Includes notes, correspondence, and publication.
  - Dymoniet, undated (Box 2, Folder 48)
  - Elephants, 1961 (Box 2, Folder 49)
    Includes news clipping and correspondence.
  - End of Siesta, 1977-1981 (Box 2, Folder 50)
    No photographs. Includes casting paperwork and sales record.
  - Ewald Medal, 1986-1987 (Box 2, Folder 51)
    No photographs. Includes notes and correspondence.
  - Fermi, Enrico, 1977-1981, undated (Box 2, Folder 52)
    Includes newsletter and correspondence.
  - Filly at Sunset, 1974-1976 (Box 2, Folder 53)
  - Flight, 1968-1988 (Box 2, Folder 54)
    Includes correspondence, news clippings, notes, negatives, color transparency, and 35-mm slides.
  - Flower Seller, undated (Box 2, Folder 55)
  - Folk Singer (Folk Music), undated (Box 2, Folder 56)
  - Fountains, undated (Box 2, Folder 57)
    Includes sketch and 35-mm slides.
  - From the Sea (Lg), 1976 (Box 2, Folder 58)
    Includes sales record and correspondence.
  - Fuller, Buckminster, 1976 (Box 2, Folder 59)
  - Future Winner, 1981-1984 (Box 2, Folder 60)
    No photographs. Includes sales record.
  - Ghayroka (4 hrs. & 8 hrs.), 1978-1982 (Box 2, Folder 61)
    Includes sales record, correspondence, and casting certificates.
  - The Gift, 1978 (Box 2, Folder 62)
  - Gilpin, Laura, 1973-1986 (Box 2, Folder 63-64)
    Includes biographical material, news clippings, exhibition and publicity material, 35-mm slides, and negatives.
  - Giraffe Family, 1982 (Box 2, Folder 65)
  - Gordios, undated (Box 2, Folder 66)
  - Graham, Susan, undated (Box 2, Folder 67)
  - Greeting, 1988 (Box 2, Folder 68)
    Includes notes, correspondence, publicity, negative, 35-mm slides, and color transparencies. See also Letitia.
  - Guitar Players, 1965, undated (Box 2, Folder 69)
    Includes news clippings and publicity.
  - Hank's Pleasure, 1978-1980 (Box 2, Folder 70)
    No photographs. Includes sales record and casting records.
  - Happiness, 1982-1989, undated (Box 2, Folder 71)
    Includes sales record, casting records, invoice, and 35-mm slides.
  - Happiness (Terra Cotta), undated (Box 2, Folder 72)
  - Happy Afternoon, 1982, undated (Box 2, Folder 73)
    No photographs. Includes correspondence, casting records, 35-mm slides.
  - High Noon at the Ranch, undated (Box 2, Folder 74)
  - Horses (Terra Cotta), 1963 (Box 2, Folder 75)
  - Intermission, undated (Box 2, Folder 76)
  - Iris Flowers, 1963 (Box 2, Folder 77)
  - Isadora Reflected, 1988 (Box 2, Folder 78)
    Includes notes, correspondence, and invoice.
  - Kelsey, Frances, undated (Box 2, Folder 79)
    Includes negatives and 35-mm slides.
  - Knox, Andrew (and pet snake), 1968-1985 (Box 2, Folder 80)
  - Lamb (font cover, Good Shepherd Methodist Church, Waldorf, MD), 1969, undated (Box 2, Folder 81)
    Includes correspondence, Guild for Religious Architecture merit award certificate, and 35-mm slide.
  - Letitia, undated (Box 2, Folder 82)
    Includes sales record, correspondence, and negatives. See also Greeting.
  - Life Cry, 1975, undated (Box 2, Folder 83)
  - Lioness with Cubs, 1983-1984, undated (Box 2, Folder 84)
    Includes correspondence, clippings, sketch, casting paperwork, 35-mm slides, and negatives.
  - Listening to Music, undated (Box 2, Folder 85)
  - Llamas, 1968-1970, undated (Box 2, Folder 86)
    Includes clippings.
  - Louisville Zoo, undated (Box 2, Folder 87)
  - Maid to Please and New Born Floa, 1974, undated (Box 2, Folder 88)
    No photographs. Includes notice of edition curtailment, note, and printed material.
  - Making Friends, 1981, undated (Box 2, Folder 89)
    Includes casting records.
  - Marit, Marina, 1981 (Box 2, Folder 90)
  - Medical Examiner's Building, undated (Box 2, Folder 91)
    Includes statement and negatives.
  - Meem, John G. and Faith, 1980-1982, undated (Box 2, Folder 92)
    Includes sketch, correspondence, castings records, and clippings.
  - Memories of Assisi, 1983, undated (Box 2, Folder 93)
    Includes sales record and 35-mm slide.
  - Menorah, undated (Box 2, Folder 94)
  - Miller, Nel, undated (Box 2, Folder 95)
  - Miscellaneous Maquettes, circa 1960-1980 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Mithra, 1978-1984, undated (Box 3, Folder 2)
    Includes sales record, correspondence, and notice of edition curtailment.
  - Moment in Time, undated (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Moniet el Nefous and Tatumi, undated (Box 3, Folder 4)
    Includes news clippings and negative.
  - Moscow, Alan, 1966, undated (Box 3, Folder 5)
    Includes biographical notes and publication.
  - Moses (SM), 1983, undated (Box 3, Folder 6)
    Includes sales record, notes, and correspondence.
  - Mother and Child, 1964, undated (Box 3, Folder 7)
    Includes news clippings and negatives.
  - Motherhood, undated (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Mullitz, Natalaie, 1966, undated (Box 3, Folder 9)
    Includes publication.
  - Music, undated (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Musk Oxen, 1981-1986, undated (Box 3, Folder 11)
    Includes casting records and news clippings.
  - Neutra, Richard, n.d,. 1969-1985 (Box 3, Folder 12)
    Includes news clippings, notes, and correspondence.
  - New Born Foal, undated (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - New Step, undated (Box 3, Folder 14)
    Includes correspondence and 35-mm slide.
  - Night Flight, undated (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - Nightwatchers, 1974, undated (Box 3, Folder 16)
    Includes casting paperwork, correspondence, negative, and 35-mm slide.
  - North Americans, 1980-1984, undated (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - O'Keeffe, Georgia, 1967-1989, undated (Box 3, Folder 18-19)
    Includes correspondence, notes, invoices, news clippings, slides, and negatives.
  - On the Plains, undated (Box 3, Folder 20)
  - Oppenheimer, Robert, 1967-1975, undated (Box 3, Folder 21)
    Includes correspondence, invoices, a loan agreement, printed materials, and a publication.
  - Orihi Antelope (Antelope and Fawn), 1982, undated (Box 3, Folder 22)
    Includes casting records, 35-mm slides, and negatives.
  - Orihi Antelope (Lg.), 1981, undated (Box 3, Folder 23)
  - Papas, Sophocles, undated (Box 3, Folder 24)
  - Paperweights (Bull, Odontoglossum Orchid, Phalaenopsis Orchid, Pony, Rooster, Tiger), 1982-1983 (Box 3, Folder 25)
    No photographs. Includes sales records.
  - The Pet Show (Le Bonheur Concern for Children Award), 1983, undated (Box 3, Folder 26)
    Includes sketches, correspondence, clippings, publicity, negatives, and 35-mm slides.
  - Phoenix, 1981-1986, undated (Box 3, Folder 27)
    Includes correspondence, notes, invitation to unveiling, foundry certificate of casting, clippings, 35-mm slides, color transparencies, and negatives.
  - Phoenix (Plexiglass), undated (Box 3, Folder 28)
  - Polingaysi (Elizabeth White), 1974-1983, undated (Box 3, Folder 29)
    Includes publicity, printed material, and correspondence.
  - Puzzle, 1973-1985, undated (Box 3, Folder 30)
    Includes casting records and correspondence.
  - Question, undated (Box 3, Folder 31)
  - Quick Lightning, 1971-1980, undated (Box 3, Folder 32)
    Includes sales record, printed material, and casting record.
  - Rashad (Arabian Stallion), undated (Box 3, Folder 33)
  - Real Wind, undated (Box 3, Folder 34)
    Includes news clippings, negatives, and notes.
  - Rios, Jesus, 1975-1988, undated (Box 3, Folder 35)
    Includes correspondence, printed matter, and negatives.
  - Ripley, S. Dillon, 1976-1978, undated (Box 3, Folder 36)
    Includes check stubs, news clippings, correspondence, and notes.
  - Rising Above the Clouds, undated (Box 3, Folder 37)
  - Ritzenberg, Katie, undated (Box 3, Folder 38)
    Includes printing plate and 35-mm slide.
  - Rocky Mountain Goats, undated (Box 3, Folder 39)
    Includes note.
  - Rudel, Julius, 1977-1983, undated (Box 3, Folder 40)
    Includes notes, invoices, correspondence, sketches, news clippings, negatives, and slides.
  - Sabellina and Samantha, 1976-1989, undated (Box 3, Folder 41)
    Includes correspondence and casting paperwork.
  - St. Mark's Lutheran Church, Springfield, Va. (Family), 1969, undated (Box 3, Folder 42)
    Includes notes, illustrated cover of Lutheran Forum magazine, miscellaneous printed material, and negatives.
  - Saveressing, Frances, undated (Box 3, Folder 43)
  - Segovia, Andrés, undated (Box 3, Folder 44)
  - Sentinels, undated (Box 3, Folder 45)
  - Simmental Calf, undated (Box 3, Folder 46)
  - Sixty Miles per Hour, 1975-1980, undated (Box 3, Folder 47)
    Includes sales record, correspondence, casting paperwork, 35-mm slides, and negatives.
  - Somewhere a Bird, undated (Box 3, Folder 48)
    Includes negatives, clides, and color transparencies.
  - Song, undated (Box 3, Folder 49)
    Includes negatives and slides.
  - Southwest Wind, undated (Box 3, Folder 50)
  - Spring Time Leap, 1976, undated (Box 3, Folder 51)
  - Stovall, Lou, undated (Box 3, Folder 52)
  - Sung, Dato David L.F., 1970-1975, undated (Box 3, Folder 53)
    Includes correspondence, notes, and printed material.
  - Swains, undated (Box 3, Folder 54)
  - Teller, Edward, 1980-1981, undated (Box 3, Folder 55)
    Includes correspondence and notes.
  - Tennis Players, 1967-1970, undated (Box 3, Folder 56)
    Includes correspondence, notes, news clippings, and printed material.
  - Thanksgiving, undated (Box 3, Folder 57)
  - Theater Guild, 1982 (Box 3, Folder 58)
  - Time Figure, undated (Box 3, Folder 59)
  - Tonto Bars Hank, 1980, undated (Box 3, Folder 60)
    Includes casting paperwork and printed material.
  - Twilight, undated (Box 3, Folder 61)
  - Unicorn with Maiden, undated (Box 3, Folder 62)
  - Vantage Point, undated (Box 3, Folder 63)
    Includes printed material.
  - Water Buffalo, 1982, undated (Box 3, Folder 64)
    Includes casting records and 35-mm slide.
  - Who Goes There, 1981, undated (Box 3, Folder 65)
  - Whoopee!, 1982, undated (Box 3, Folder 66)
    Includes casting records and slide.
  - Witness to the Long Walk, undated (Box 3, Folder 67)
  - Wonder is the Beginning of Wisdom, undated (Box 3, Folder 68)
    Includes correspondence, negatives, color transparencies, and 35-mm slide. See also Yugoslavia.
  - Work Horse, 1984, undated (Box 3, Folder 69)
    Includes correspondence and negatives.
  - Yugoslavia, 1971-1981, undated (Box 3, Folder 70)
    Includes sketches, correspondence, notes, printed material, 35-mm slides, and negatives. See also Wonder is the Beginning of Wisdom.
- Subject Files, circa 1924-1985; Series 4; 1 Linear feet Box 4, OV 7